The Alpinist is a documentary, adventure film directed by Peter Mortimer.
Marc-André Leclerc, an exceptional climber, has made
solo his religion and ice his homeland.
When filmmaker Peter Mortimer begins his film, he places his camera at the base of a British Columbia
cliff and waits patiently for the star climber to come down to answer his questions.
Marc André, a little uncomfortable, prefers to return to the depths of the forest
where he lives in a tent with his girlfriend Brette Harrington.
In the heart of winter, Peter films vertiginous solos on fragile ice.
He tries to make appointments with the climber who is never there and does not seem really concerned by
this camera pointed at him "For me, it would not be a solo if there was someone else" .
Marc-André is thus, the "pure light" of the mountaineers of his time, which marvel Barry
Blanchard, Alex Honnold or Reinhold Messner, interviewed in the film.
An event film for an extraordinary character.
Self, played by Marc-André Leclerc.
Self, played by Brette Harrington.
Self, played by Alex Honnold.
Self, played by Reinhold Messner.
Self (archive footage), played by Ueli Steck.
Self (archive footage), played by Dean Potter.
The Alpinist is a 2021 American documentary film directed by Peter Mortimer and Nick Rosen about Marc-André
Leclerc, a free-spirited and little-known 23-year-old Canadian rock climber, ice climber, and alpinist.
From 2015 to 2016, a film crew followed Leclerc as he solo climbed some of the
most difficult and dangerous alpine climbing routes in the world.
The film was produced by Sender Films and Red Bull Media House, and
distributed by Universal Pictures and Roadside Attractions.
The film was given a limited release on September
10, 2021, in the United States.
It received generally positive reviews from film
critics and from the climbing media.
The film explores themes of mountain, biography, climbing,
patagonia, argentina, mountain climbing.